West Coast Line fonds
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department
West Coast Line fonds
1966 - 1985
F-81
Q106642979
25 cm of textual records
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department Maggie Benston Student Services Building, Rm. 0400 8888 University Dr. Burnaby British Columbia Canada V5A 1S6 Telephone: 778.782.3805 Email: archives@sfu.ca http://www.sfu.ca/archives
West Coast Line
West Coast Review was a magazine of the arts published by the West Coast Review Society with the support of SFU. Established in 1966 by Fred Candelaria, a professor of English, the magazine published music, drama, fiction, poetry, photography, drawings and etchings as well as articles as reviews. The magazine had a policy of promoting new Canadian talent. In addition to financial assistance from the University, the journal received funding at various times from private and governmental agencies, the Simon Fraser Student Society, advertising, and subscriptions.
West Coast Review was initially published three times a year until 1969 when it became a quarterly journal. It periodically devoted special issues to a particular genre or theme such as West Coast Photographers.
In 1990, West Coast Review was succeeded by West Coast Line.
published
Full
Revised
Title of the fonds is based on the provenance.
The materials were arranged by the Archivist.
Arts and culture; Communications
Unknown.
All accessions have been processed as of September 2002. Further accruals to the fonds are expected from time to time.
See the catalogue of the W.A.C. Bennett Library for a complete run of West Coast Review and West Coast Line.
Some files may contain personal or confidential information. Access to these files may be restricted as stipulated by Archives policy or the donor. Files marked 'pending review' must be reviewed by an archivist prior to release, and as a result of the review access restrictions may apply. Please see the file lists and consult the archivist for more details.
Series descriptions and file lists are available.
- Administrative records, 1966 - 1984; F-81-1; 13 cm of textual records
  published
  Series consists of records relating to the general administrative activities of the editor and staff of West Coast Review. Topics documented include the establishment of the journal, liaison with writers, and efforts to secure funding through grants, advertising, and donors. Series consists primarily of correspondence.
  - General Correspondence, 1976 - 1978; F-81-1-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 81-1)
    Textual records
    Pending review
  - General Correspondence, 1979 - 1982; F-81-1-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 81-1)
  - General Correspondence, 1983 - 1984; F-81-1-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 81-1)
  - Correspondence - Administration (internal), 1967 - 1982; F-81-1-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 81-1)
  - Correspondence - review copies, 1981 - 1984; F-81-1-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 81-1)
  - Budget Records, 1977 - 1981; F-81-1-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 81-1)
  - Advertising, 1969 - 1981; F-81-1-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 81-1)
  - B.C. Cultural Services, 1981; F-81-1-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 81-1)
  - Advertising Survey, 1983; F-81-1-0-0-9 (Archival box - standard 81-1)
  - Canada Council, 1979 - 1980; F-81-1-0-0-10 (Archival box - standard 81-1)
  - Grant Applications for new West Coast Photographers, 1981 - 1982; F-81-1-0-0-11 (Archival box - standard 81-1)
  - Clippings File, 1966 - 1969; F-81-1-0-0-12 (Archival box - standard 81-1)
  - President's Medal Awards, 1967 - 1970; F-81-1-0-0-13 (Archival box - standard 81-1)
- Publication records, 1967 - 1985; F-81-2; 13 cm of textual records
  Series consists of records relating to the publication of particular thematic issues of West Coast Review as well as general files relating to the printing of the journal. Includes correspondence, selected copies of West Coast Review, invoices, and a manuscript record book.
  - North West Coast Poetry, 1977; F-81-2-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 81-2)
  - Asian-Canadian Issue, 1981; F-81-2-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 81-2)
    Open, reading room
    Reviewed for access (Dec 12, 2023) – File includes records that contain some individuals' personal contact information. File can be accessed in the Archives' reading room, but will be redacted in any digital access copies made by Archives.
  - New: West Coast Photographers - Correspondence, 1981 - 1982; F-81-2-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 81-2)
  - New: West Coast Photographers - Production, 1981 - 1982; F-81-2-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 81-2)
  - North West Coast Fiction, 1984; F-81-2-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 81-2)
  - Morris Printing Company, 1967 - 1970; F-81-2-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 81-2)
  - Intermedia Press, 1977 - 1981; F-81-2-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 81-2)
  - Manuscript Record Book, 1982 - 1985; F-81-2-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 81-2)